# **STEVE ROLLINS FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

- coding61.sr@gmail.com
- **\** 206-940-5274
- North Bend, WA
- in steven-rollins
- greenhornsr

Full Stack Web Developer with over 10 years of prior experience as a mobility sales representative. Tech stack includes: HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, PYTHON, REACT, REDUX, HOOKS, NODEJS, ANGULAR, MONGODB, about developing quality applications that improve users' quality of life & building highquality experiences for end users. Eager to continue to grow as a contributor with an equally strong team that is passionate

#### **INTERESTS INCLUDE:**

Molding Digital Clay(Coding)!

**Combat Sports** 

Basketball

Football

### **VOLUNTEERING:**

Mt. Si View (SVSD) Head Coach Basketball Developing, leading, teaching 8-11 year old boys basic and advanced basketball skills.

i-9 Sports Flag Football Assistant Teaching 6-7 year old boys Flag Football

I-9 Sports · Soccer Assistant Coach Teaching 4-5 year olds how to play soccer.

### Skills

WEB DEVELOPMENT: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, React, Redux, SQL-Lite, REST, GraphQL, Python, PostgreSQL, Less/Sass, Flask, Django, Angular, Jest, SQL

# **Projects**

ghsr-portfolio

Apr. 2020 to Current

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT

Independent project designed with intent to be a simple 1 stop stop about me for any employer / recruiter.

- Folder/file structure was done with simplicity and reusability in mind.
- Includes a ticker, a summary of me and my work, as well as links for my Github, LinkedIn, Resume and a streamlined method to email me.

URL to portfolio site: https://steven-d-rollins-portfolio.netlify.app/

Chicago Array of Things

June 2019 to June 2019

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT | REDUX | NODE.JS | EXPRESS | KNEX | POSTGRESQL | PYTHON

Chicago Array of Things was an ambitious project to allow users to visit our site to view preferred data collected by the Chicago AOT sensors.

- · Our team of 9 students from different checkpoints of WEB and Data Science curriculum were expected to build this in 4 days!
- Solely responsible for working with the Back End to produce a Front End that included a Client side Authorization, Login, Registration and producing a Query interface for the user that would present a graph returned from the Back End / DS team linked to the chosen query.

URL to deployed site: https://chicago-aot.netlify.app/

YELP-FEELERS

Oct. 2019 to Oct. 2019

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT | REDUX | NODE.JS | EXPRESS | KNEX | POSTGRESQL | PYTHON |

YELP FEELERS was also a cross-functional team project tasked with building an application that leveraged the YELP API to produce modified review results based on user sentiment analysis.

- · Our team consisted of 8 students from different checkpoints of WEB and Data Science curriculum and were expected to complete this in 4 days.
- My responsibilities included Leading the project team as well as producing the BackEnd of the project.
- Utilized Node JS and Express to set up the server environment and API; used KNEX to translate JS to SQL and deploy the PostgreSQL Database; also used the API and JWT to validate client side user data sent to the Backend.

URL to deployed site: https://practical-lamport-cc4fcf.netlify.app/

# **Employment**

Lambda School

Team Lead(REMOTE)

North Bend, WA Aug. 2019 to Nov. 2019

Full Time position. Primary responsibility was to support the learning and professional growth of Lambda Students. Often required mentoring students in the understanding of HTML, CSS, JS, REACT, HOOKS, REDUX, CONTEXT, EXPRESS, NODE.js, SQLITE3/PSQL and other associated concepts.

Bellevue, WA

Major Accounts Manager - Healthcare

June 2013 to May 2015

Responsible for identifying and introducing HIPAA compliant partner solutions that solved mobility needs of western Washington's largest healthcare systems; keeping security, industry regulations, budgets and most importantly...patient safety front of mind.

Verizon Wireless

Denver, CO Nov. 2007 to June 2013

**Business Account Executive** 

New business customer procurement, management of existing customer base for businesses that had employee counts mostly ranging from 5-499.

## **Education**

Lambda School Coding Dojo

Apr. 2019 to Current

Oct. 2016 to Jan. 2017